A. Zeno Shindler American Indian Photograph Collection 1852-1869 Mss.970.1.Sh6
American Philosophical Society
A. Zeno Shindler American Indian Photograph Collection
1852-1869
Mss.970.1.Sh6
American Philosophical Society
0.5 Linear feet 96 photographs
A shadowy figure at best, the artist Antonio Zeno Shindler worked at the Smithsonian Institution from after the Civil War until the turn of the 20th century, specializing in ethnographic subjects. He was responsible for printing or taking a large number of photographs of American Indians exhibited there in 1869. The 95 studio portraits in the Shindler Collection were part of a suite of 301 images that comprised the first photographic exhibition at the Smithsonian, and that are documented in the catalogue Photographic Portraits of North American Indians in the Gallery of the Smithsonian Institution (1867). The individuals depicted were members of delegations sent to Washington during the years 1852, 1857-1858, and 1867-1869 from the following nations: Cherokee, Cheyenne, Chippewa, Choctaw, Dakota Sioux (Brule, Miniconjou, Sans Arc, Santee, Sisseton, Two-Kettle, Yankton), Osage, Pawnee, Ponca, Potawatomi, Sac and Fox, Seminole, and Ute. Shindler printed the earlier photographs (mostly taken by the McClees Gallery) and was photographer for the later delegations.
Shindler, A. Zeno(Antonio Zeno),1823-1899.
Bibliography
Photographic Portraits of North American Indians in the Gallery of the Smithsonian Institution. Smithsonian Institution Miscellaneous Collections 216 (1867). Call no.: 506.73 Sm65x.
Fleming, Paula Richardson, Native American Photography at the Smithsonian: The Shindler Catalogue (Washington, D.C.: Smithsonian, 2003).
Related Archival Materials note
The APS has several rich photographic collections documenting Native Americans, including the Frank Speck Photographic Collection and the papers of William N. Fenton and A. I. Hallowell.
A more complete collection of the Shindler Photographs is available at the Smithsonian Institution.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Acquired from the Smithsonian Institution, ca.1869.
Scope and Contents note
The 95 studio portraits in the Shindler Collection were part of a suite of 301 images that comprised the first photographic exhibition at the Smithsonian, and that are documented in the catalogue Photographic Portraits of North American Indians in the Gallery of the Smithsonian Institution (1867). The individuals depicted were members of delegations sent to Washington during the years 1852, 1857-1858, and 1867-1869 from the following nations: Cherokee, Cheyenne, Chippewa, Choctaw, Dakota Sioux (Brule, Miniconjou, Sans Arc, Santee, Sisseton, Two-Kettle, Yankton), Osage, Pawnee, Ponca, Potawatomi, Sac and Fox, Seminole, and Ute. Shindler printed the earlier photographs (mostly taken by the McClees Gallery) and was photographer for the later delegations.
The photographs, presumably printed ca.1869, are albumen prints trimmed into ovals and mounted on Addis Gallery stock. Each photograph is identified by a reference number corresponding to the printed Smithsonian catalogue, and the titles and identifications are drawn from a manuscript list included with the Shindler Collection at the APS (usually, but not always identical to the entries in the printed catalogue). The collection contains photographs no. 1-104, with the exception of nos. 48, 54, 60, 67, 75, 76, 83, 88, and 95. The dates of these photographs were taken from Paula Richardson Fleming's Native American Photography at the Smithsonian: The Shindler Catalogue (2003), and names and other information were checked against her work. Biographical information on Shindler was also partially derived from Fleming's catalogue.
All of the photographs in this collection have been digitized. Links to the digital versions are included in the inventory. You may also view a gallery of all images here.
Biographical/Historical note
A shadowy figure at best, the artist Antonio Zeno Shindler worked at the Smithsonian Institution from after the Civil War until the turn of the 20th century, specializing in ethnographic subjects.
The visual documentation of Native American cultures became a focus of the Smithsonian Institution from within a few years of its founding in 1846. The original core of the collections consisted of a number of portraits of Indian delegates who visited Washington during the 1850s done by Charles Bird King and John Mix Stanley's paintings of Indian life. However when a fire gutted its west wing in January 1865, the Smithsonian was forced to start anew.
The Director of the Smithsonian Joseph Henry found particular support for his plans to develop a photographic gallery of Indians from two key individuals, Ferdinand V. Hayden, head of the U.S. Geological Survey, and William Henry Blackmore, an English philanthropist and founder of the Blackmore Museum in Salisbury. Blackmore loaned his personal collection of photographs to Henry in 1867, hiring Shindler to make copies of them and to help prepare the catalogue for an exhibition that was mounted in 1869, the Smithsonian's first photographic exhibit.
Born as Antonio Zeno in either Bulgaria or Romania, depending on which source for the story one prefers, Shindler was said to have left his homeland after the extermination of his family in a vendetta. Making his way to Geneva, he fell in with a Frenchman named Shindler who took him under his wing, and the two lived together in Paris, where Zeno studied art, taking the last name of his patron. Precisely when Zeno Shindler came to the United States is unknown, but by 1852, he is recorded as working as a drawing instructor at the Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts in Philadelphia, where he exhibited regularly in ensuing years. Other stories suggest that Shindler moved first to Chicago, where he lost everything in the great fire, however the chronology is surely wrong and hard evidence to support the contention that he lived there is weak.
In Philadelphia, Shindler married a young French woman, Justina Fontaine in 1852, with whom he had a daughter, Isabella, in January of the following year. The couple moved to Washington, D.C., in 1867, where Shindler took control of the prominent Robert W. Addis Photographic Gallery, successor to James Earle McClees, acquiring McClees' daguerreotypes and photographic negatives he had taken of visiting Indian delegations in the 1850s.
Shindler was slow in making copies from Blackmore's images, but his prints were instrumental in helping to mount the exhibition, Photographic Portraits of North American Indians in the Gallery of the Smithsonian Institution. He was hired by Blackmore as well to make oil paintings of some of the images.
After the exhibition, Shindler continued to work with the Smithsonian as a contract employee until he was hired full time in 1876. He remained on staff for another 23 years, doing watercolors, tinting photographs, and performing other work as a painter and artist. He died on August 9, 1899, from injuries sustained from a fall from a streetcar.
Smithsonian Institution.; Albumen prints; Cherokee Indians--Photographs; Cheyenne Indians--Photographs; Chippewa Indians--Photographs; Choctaw Indians--Photographs; Dakota Indians--Photographs; Indians of North America--Photographs; Osage Indians--Photographs; Pawnee Indians--Photographs; Photographs; Plains Indians; Ponca Indians--Photographs; Potawatomi Indians--Photographs; Sac and Fox Indians--Photographs; Seminole Indians--Photographs; Southeast Indians; Ute Indians--Photographs
- A. Zeno Shindler American Indian Photograph Collection, 1852-1869; 0.5 linear feet
  - Pa-da-ni-ha-hi, Struck by the Ree (Head Chief of the Yankton Sioux, Dakota Territory), 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 1; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - Psi-Ca-Na-Kin-Yan, Jumping Thunder (Yankton Sioux Chief, Dakota), 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 2; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - Wi-Ya-Ko-Mi, Feather in the Ear (Yankton Sioux Chief, Dakota), 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 3; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - Ma-Ga-Skan, White Swan (Yankton Sioux Chief, Dakota), 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 4; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - To-Kan-Was-Te, The Pretty Rock (Son of a Yankton Sioux Chief, Dakota), 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 5; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - Wa-Jin-ka, Little Bird (Yankton Sioux Brave, Dakota), 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 6; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - To-Ka-O-No-Pa, The One Who Catches the Enemy (Yankton Sioux Brave, Dakota), 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 7; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - Pte-Yah-Pa-Ma-Sa, The Iron Black Bird (Yankton Sioux Brave, Dakota), 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 8; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - Kna-Skin-Ya-Ma-Ni, He Walks Mad (Head Soldier of the Yankton Sioux, Dakota), 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 9; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - Wan-Mdi-Sa-Pa, Black Eagle (Yankton Sioux Brave, Dakota), 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 10; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - Wo-A-Ki-Tsi-Kan, Little Thunder (Yankton Sioux Brave, Dakota), 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 11; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - Si-Ha-Han-Ska, Longfoot (Yankton Sioux Brave, Dakota), 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 12; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - Francis Jaudron, Half Breed (Yankton Sioux Brave, Dakota), 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 13; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - Ma-Ko-Kti-Nang-Ma-Ni, The Bear That Walks Lying Down (Yankton Sioux Brave, Dakota), 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 14; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - Ta-Tsan-Op-Ki-An, Flying Pipe (Head Soldier of the Yankton Sioux, Dakota), 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 15; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - DeLaurier, Half Breed (Yankton Sioux Chief, Dakota), 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 16; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - Ta-Ta-Ka-Wa-Kan, Sacred Bull (Brulé Chief, Dakota), 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 17; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - Se-Tan-Si-Tan, Yellow Hawk (Sans Arc Chief, Dakota), 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 18; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - Se-Tan-Si-Tan, Yellow Hawk (San Arc Chief, Dakota), 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 19; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - Ma-Za-O-Ya-Ti, Iron Nation (Yankton Sioux Chief, Dakota), 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 20; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - Kah-Kah-Tah-A-Ke-Ah, The Flying Bird (Two-Kettle Sioux Chief, Dakota), 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 21; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - Ma-Ta-Wa-Yu-Mi, The Bear That Frightens (Yankton Sioux Chief, Upper Missouri, Dakota Territory), 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 22; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - Ma-Ta-Wa-Yu-Mi, The Bear That Frightens (Yankton Sioux Chief, Upper Missouri, Dakota Territory), 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 23; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - Chun-Kan-Ke-Tes-Ka, The Spotted Horse (Two-Kettle Sioux Chief, Dakota), 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 24; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - To-Ki-Ya-Wi-Ka-Kte, He Kills First (Miniconjou Chief, Dakota), 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 25; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - Na-Ji-Wa-Kan, The Sacred Ghost (Two-Kettle Sioux Brave, Dakota), 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 26; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - Ma-To-Ho-Kan-Tan-Ke, The Bear With the Big Voice (Two-Kettle Sioux Chief, Dakota), 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 27; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - Ma-To-Ho-Kan-Tan-Ke, The Bear With the Big Voice (Two-Kettle Sioux Chief, Dakota), 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 28; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - Ma-Va-Ta-Na-Han-Ska, Long Mandan (Two-Kettle Sioux Chief, Dakota), 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 29; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - Pte-Wa-Kan-Na-Gi, The Medicine Cow (Yankton Sioux Chief, Upper Missouri, Dakota Territory), 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 30; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - Ma-Ta-Sa-Be-Zi-A, The Smutty Bear (Yankton Sioux Chief, Upper Missouri, Dakota Territory), ca.1857 Dec. 13-1858 Apr. 26; 31; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Negative by McClees Gallery, printed by Shindler.
  - Tow-A-Hu-Ka-Sa-No-Pa, Two Lances (Yankton Sioux Chief, Upper Missouri, Dakota Territory), 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 32; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - Wa-Pa-Sha, Red Ensign (Chief of the Ki-Gu-ksa Band (Santee Sioux), Dakota), Age 50 years, 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 33; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - Cho-Tan-Ka-Si-Di-Na-Pe, The Flute Player (Head Man of the Wak-pe-ton Dakota (Santees), Dakota), Age 48 years, 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 34; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - Wa-Ka-Te, The Shooter (Chief of the Re-mi-ni-ca Band (Santees), Dakota), Age 45 years, 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 35; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - Hu-Sha-Sha, Red Legs (Chief of the Wak-pe-ka-te (Santees), Dakota), Age 55 years, 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 36; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - Han-Ye-Tu-Du-Ta, Scarlet Night (Head Man of the Re-Mi-Ni-Ca Band (Santees), Dakota), Age 37 years, 1867 ca.Feb. 17-24; 37; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - Wa-Mdi-Ka-Wa-Ma-Ni, He Walks Following Eagles (Wa-Pa-Shee Chief of Santees, Dakota), Age 14 years, 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 38; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - Wa-Kan-Hdi-Sa-Pa, Black Lightning (Head Man of the Ri-Ga-Ta-A-Ta-Wa Band (Santees), Dakota), Age 34 years, 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 39; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - Zi-Ka-Tan-To, Blue Bird (Wak-pe-ton Band (Santees), Dakota), Age 20 years, 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 40; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - Jus-Un-Ke-Ma-Za, His Man Horse (Man of the Co-Po-Cia Band (Santees), Dakota), 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 41; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - O-Wan-Sa-Du-Ta, Scarlet All Over (Chief of the Re-Ga-Ta O-Tou-We Band (Santees), Dakota), 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 42; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - Mok_Pi-Yu-E-Hua-Ku-Dan, Coming After the Clouds (Wak-pe-ton Band (Santees), Dakota), Age 18 years, 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 43; 1 albumen print (Box 1)
  - A-Ki-Ci-Tan-Na-Jin, The Standing Soldier (Man of the Ca-Po-Cia Band (Santees), Dakota), Age 39 years, 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 44; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - Wak-Pi-Yu-Hdi-Na-Jin, The Standing Cloud (Man of the Re-Ga-Ta O-Tou-We Band (Santees), Dakota), 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 45; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - Wa-Kan-Na, The Sacred (Man of the Wak-Pe-Ku-Te Band (Santees), Dakota), Age 18 years, 1867 ca.Feb.-Apr.; 46; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - John Ross (Head Chief of the Cherokees, Indian Territory West of Arkansas), Died in Washington, Aug. 1866, ca.1858 Apr. 16; 47; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
    Negative by the McClees Gallery.
  - O-To-Wa, The Sucker (A Po-To-Wa-Ta-Mi Councillor, Kansas), ca.1858 Dec.-1859 Mar.; 49; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - Wi-Ga-Sa-Pi, The Whip (Chief of the Ponchas, Dakota), ca.1858 Dec.-1859 Mar.; 50; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - Hin-Han-Du-Ta, The Red Owl (Chief of the Mde-Wa-Kan-Ton Sioux, Dakota), ca.1858 Mar.-June; 51; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - Wzhi-Kian, Thunder Coming Down to the Ground (A Po-To-Wa-Ta-Mi Councillor, Kansas), ca.1858 Dec.-1859 Mar.; 52; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - Upi-T-Ya-Hde-A, Tail-Feather Joined (Wa-Pe-Ton Sioux Chief, Dakota), ca.1858 Mar.-June; 53; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - Wa-Mdi-Tan-Ka, The Great Eagle (Med-Wa-Kan-Ton Sioux Chief, Dakota), ca.1858 Mar.-June; 55; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - At-Pe-Tu-To-Ka-Tsha, The Other Day (Wa-Pe-Ton Sioux Warrior, Dakota), ca.1858 Mar.-June; 56; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - He-Hu-Te-Dan, Little Short Horn (Si-Si-Ton Sioux Warrior, Dakota), ca.1858 Mar.-June; 57; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - Psi-Ka-Wa-Kin-Yan, Jumping Thunder (Yankton Sioux Warrior, Dakota), ca.1858 Dec.-1859 Apr.; 58; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - A-Ha-Ka-Ma-Ni, The Walking Elk (Yankton Sioux Warrior, Dakota), ca.1858 Dec.-1859 Apr.; 59; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - Mo-Ka-Ho-Ka, Fish Rising Above the Water (Principal Chief of the Sac and Foxes, Kansas), ca.1858 Dec.-1859 Mar.; 61; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - Ne-Sha-Du-Si-Di-Te-Zi-Ka, The Chief Whom They Look Upon (Principal Chief of the Republican Pawnees, Nebraska), ca.1858 Dec.-1859 Apr.; 62; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - Na-Sa-Wa-Kwut, The Bear in the Fork of a Tree (Principal Chief of the Sac and Foxes, Kansas), ca.1858 Dec.-1859 Mar.; 63; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - Pi-Ta-Ne-Sha-A-Du, Man-and-Chief (Principal Chief of the Pawnees, Nebraska), ca.1858 Dec.-1859 Apr.; 64; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - La-Hak-Tan-Du-He-Sha-A-Du, Medicine Pipe Chief (Chief of the Grand Pawnees, Nebraska), ca.1858 Dec.-1859 Apr.; 65; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - Ne-Sha-Re-Ru-Re-Ra Hi-Kute, the Brave Chief (Republican Pawnee Chief, Nebraska), ca.1858 Dec.-1859 Apr.; 66; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - Pug-A-No-Ke-Shick, Hole in the Day (Head Chief of the Chippewas, Minnesota), 1858 ca.Mar. 13; 68; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - He-Ka-Ka Nang-Zhe, The Standing Elk (Yankton Sioux Warrior, Dakota), ca.1858 Dec.-1859 Apr.; 69; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - La-Ka-Ko, The Gray Fox (Chief of the Sac and Foxes, Kansas), ca.1858 Dec.-1859 Mar.; 70; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - Sha-Kpi, Six (Mde-Wa-Kan-Ton Sioux Chief, Dakota), ca.1858 Mar.-June; 71; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - Oh-Lach-Ta-Miko, Billy Bowlegs (Seminole Chief, Indian Territory West of Arkansas), ca.1852; 72; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
    Original image probably by John Hawley Clarke.
  - Ti-Ro-Wot-Ka-To-Huk, The Conqueror (Grand Pawnee Chief, Nebraska), ca.1858 Dec.-1859 Apr.; 73; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - La-Tang-Ka-Yang-Ke, The Running Bull (Yankton Sioux Warrior, Dakota), ca.1858 Dec.-1859 Apr.; 74; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - Battle Between Ponkas and Sioux (Painted by To-Tay-Go-Nai (Standing Buffalo), a young Ponca Warrior, [1858]; 77; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - Col. P. P. Pitchlynn (Choctaw delegate, Choctaw Nation), ca.1868 Mar. 31; 78; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - Rev. Israel Folsom (Choctaw delegate, Choctaw Nation), ca.1868 Mar. 31; 79; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - A Chief of the Osage Indians (Kansas) [probably Baptiste Lapillier, a Winnebago Chief], ca.1858 Feb.; 80; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
    Negative by McClees Gallery.
  - Group of Cheyenne Indian Chiefs (Nebraska) [l. to r.: White Antepole, Alights on a Cloud, Little Chief], 1858; 81; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
    Original daguerreotype by John H. Fitzgibbon.
  - Sobita (Head Chief of the Capote Utes and Brother of Carrisa, Head Chief of the Utas, Colorado Territory; New Mexico), ca.1868 Mar. 31; 82; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - Ni-Co-Rod, Green Leaf (Uta Chief, Colorado), ca.1868 Mar. 31; 84; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - Pe-A-Oh, Black-Tail Deer (Uta Chief, Colorado), ca.1868 Mar. 31; 85; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - Shu-Ri-Pi, Lodge Pole's Son (Uta Chief, Colorado), ca.1868 Mar. 31; 86; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - Chip-Pin, Always Riding (Uta Chief, Colorado), ca.1868 Mar. 31; 87; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - Wa-Com-Mo (Chief of the Foxes, Kansas), ca.1868 Mar. 31; 88; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - Che-Ko-Shuk (Head Chief of the Foxes, Kansas), ca.1868 Mar. 31; 89; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - Mo-Ko-Ho-Ko, Fish Rising Above the Water (Chief of the Sacs, Kansas), ca.1868 Mar. 31; 90; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - Uk-Wha-Ho-Ko, Fish Floating to the Shore (Chief of the Sacs, Kansas), ca.1868 Mar. 31; 91; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - Pa-Tek-Kwa (Chief of the Sacs, Kansas), ca.1868 Mar. 31; 92; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - Group of Four Ponka Chiefs (l. to r. Ash-Nom-e-Kah-Ga-He, Lone Chief; To-Ton-Ga Un-Zhe, Standing Buffalo; Wah-Ga-Sa-Pi, Iron Whip; Wast-Eh-Com-Ma-Ni, Fast Walker), ca.1868 Mar. 31; 93; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - Col. Lewis Downing (Head Chief of the Cherokees, Cherokee Nation), ca.1868 Mar. 31; 95; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - Capt. Arch[ibald] Scraper (Cherokee Delegate, Cherokee Nation), ca.1868 Mar. 31; 96; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - J[efferson] Porum Davis (Cherokee Delegate, Cherokee Nation), ca.1868 Mar. 31; 97; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - Samuel Smith (Cherokee Delegate, Cherokee Nation), ca.1868 Mar. 31; 98; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - Col. [William Penn] Adair (Cherokee Delegate, Cherokee Nation), ca.1868 Mar. 31; 99; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - H. C. Reese (Cherokee Delegate, Cherokee Nation), ca.1868 Mar. 31; 100; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - Col. Faunceway Battice (Choctaw Delegate, Choctaw Nation), ca.1868 Mar. 31; 101; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - War Dance of the Yankton Sioux (Dakota) [l. to r. Struck by the Ree, White Swan, Long Foot, Little Bird, Black Eagle], ca.1867 Feb.-Apr.; 102; 1 albumen print (Box 2)
  - Group of four Utah Indians [l. to r. Nick-a-a-god, Green Leaf; Pe-ah, Black Tailed Deer; Chippin, Always Riding; and Suriap, Lodge Pole's Son], ca.1868 Mar. 31; 103; 1 albumen print (Box 2)